untangle.com 2019-08-17

# Privacy | Untangle

_Last Updated 03/30/2018_

### General

Untangle, Inc. (“Untangle”) respects the privacy of our customers, business partners, and employees. We want to be clear about how you can protect your privacy and how we use the information you provide as you use Untangle’s products, services, and sites.

For purposes of compliance with the European Union’s General Data Privacy Regulation, Untangle will be known as the “Controller” of the personal information about you. We only collect basic personal information required to conduct business. This includes information such as first and last name, address, email, and phone number.

We are required under United States tax law to retain basic information relating to your business with Untangle for a minimum of 7 years. The information includes the basic personal information listed above. If you no longer have a business relationship with Untangle after the seven-year period, Untangle will remove that information.

### Our privacy policy explains:

  * What information we collect and why we collect it

  * How we use the information 

  * How to access, update, or remove the information.

We strive to make this policy simple to read and understand. Your privacy is important to us. If you have questions, please [contact us](mailto:support@untangle.com).

### Information We Collect

Untangle collects information to provide better products and services to our customers. The types of information we collect include first and last name, address, phone number, email, user IDs, location data, passwords, contact preferences, educational and employment background, job interest data and the IP address and URL of the website that sent you to the Untangle site. We collect information in the following ways.

### The information you give us: 

For example, many of Untangle’s products and services require you to create an Untangle account. When you do, we will ask for personal information like your name, email, address, telephone number. If you perform a business transaction with us, we may also collect financial information such as credit card number or other data.

### Information we generate by use of our products, services, and sites.

We collect information as you use Untangle’s products, services, and websites. This information includes:

### Device Information:

We collect device-specific information which can include hardware model, version information, unique device identifiers, device event information such as applications installed, licensing information, crash information, system activity, hardware settings, network information, and installation information. Untangle may associate your unique device identifiers with your Untangle Account.

### Telephony log information:

Untangle may collect your phone number, calling-party number, time and date of calls, duration of calls and types of calls.

### Cookies:

Untangle uses various technologies to collect and store information when you visit our sites, including using cookies or similar technologies to identify your browser or device. We use these technologies to provide an enhanced user experience and analyze traffic to our sites and applications.

### How we use the information we collect

We will only use the information we collect about your use of our products, services, and sites for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy and when the law allows us to do so. We will generally use your personal information on the following lawful grounds:

  * Where the use of your personal information is necessary for the performance of a contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.

  * Where the use is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate commercial interests (or those of a third party).

  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

Specifically, we use your information to deliver products/services to you, to improve our products and services, to bill you for products/services you purchased, to communicate with you concerning your account, support, or customer services issues, and to provide automated software updates for Untangle products.

Occasionally, we may use your information to contact you to complete surveys that we use for marketing and quality assurance purposes. We may combine personal information collected online with information you provide to Untangle through other sources such as trade shows or seminars. Also, we may use your information to improve the content of our sites, products, and services; to alert you to product upgrades, updates and renewal information regarding your product; and to share special offers, product announcements and other new services from Untangle, where, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving such information.

Untangle may collect information about your use of our sites, such as the types of services used and how many users we support daily. This information obtained in aggregate form, without identifying any user or their behaviors individually. Untangle may use this aggregated, non-identifying data for statistical analysis, marketing or similar promotional purposes.

Untangle will ask you for your consent before using information for purposes not detailed in our Privacy Policy. You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us using the details below.

### When Untangle May Share Your Personal Information

We do not share personal information with any organization, business, or individual unless one of the following reasons apply.

### For external processing:

We may share the information you provide to our business partners acting on our behalf for the sole purpose, and only to the extent needed, to support you in compliance with this Privacy Policy. For example, when you provide information to make a purchase, we share payment information with banks and other entities that process payments or provide financial services. We may also work with third parties for fraud prevention and risk reduction. We will NOT provide your information to any third party for marketing or other purposes.

### For legal reasons:

We will share personal information with companies, organizations or individuals if we have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation, or disclosure for:

  * Meeting any law, regulation, legal process or government enforcement

  * Enforcing licensing or terms of service including investigations of potential violators

  * Detect, prevent, or address fraud, security, or technical issues

  * Protect against harm to rights, property, or safety of Untangle, our users or the public as required or permitted by law.

### Security of Personal Information

Untangle is committed to taking reasonable efforts to secure the personal information you choose to provide us. To protect the privacy of any personal information you may have provided, Untangle employs industry-standard controls including physical access controls as well as cybersecurity measures including, but not limited to, firewalls, intrusion detection, and network monitoring.

### Links to Non-Untangle Web Sites and Third Parties

Untangle sites may provide links to third-party websites for your convenience and information. If you access those links, you will leave the Untangle site. Untangle does not control those sites or their privacy practices, nor endorse or make any representations about third-party sites. We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy of any company before submitting your personal information.

### Updating and Access to Your Personal Information and Privacy Preferences

Under certain circumstances, you have the right to access, correct, or remove your personal information at any time. You can also object to or restrict the use of your personal information, or request the transfer of your personal information to a third party. 

Also, you can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the unsubscribe links on any marketing message sent to you or by contacting us at any time. Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal information provided to us as a result of you interaction with us.

You may access, request a copy of, correct, or remove your personal information and privacy preferences (such as whether you wish to receive promotional communications from Untangle) by visiting 

<https://support.untangle.com/hc/en-us>

Untangle, Inc.  
100 W. San Fernando St, Suite 565  
San Jose, CA 95113  
USA

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time. The use of your information is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time of use. Please check the “Last Updated” legend at the top of this page to see when this Privacy Policy was last revised.
